Guide to the Donald F. Clark Collection circa 1642-1920 MS 118
New-York Historical Society
- Pickard, Richard. Letter of resignation as Churchman. Warwick, 1840 March 28 (Box 6, Item 633)
- Pickhard, Richard, minister of Baptist Church. Subscribers promise to pay fees, 1840 May 4 (Box 2, Item 223)
- Lands, John B., Clerk of Zion Church, Cornwall. Certification that Joseph & Fanny Brooks are members, 1840 October 20 (Box 2, Item 229)
- Subscribers for the year 1840 (Box 2, Item 224)
  Probably related to item 223.
- Hunter, J. Executor's deed. Orange County, 1841 February 6 (Box 3, Item 437)
  Samuel W. Eager
- Sly, Arthur B., Overseer of Poor in Newburgh. Receipt to Keeper of Orange County Poor House, 1841 April 26 (Box 2, Item 184)
- Pickhard, Richard, minister of Warwick Baptist Church. Subscribers promise to pay fees, 1841 May 1 (Box 2, Item 226)
- New York & Erie Railroad, Orange County. Certificate of location, 1841 September 10 (Box 2, Item 212)
- Subscribers for the year commencing May 1841 (Box 2, Item 225)
  Probably related to items 223 and 224.
- Arbuckle, Anne M. Petition to state legislature for care of the poor. Blooming Grove, Orange County, NY, 1844 April (Box 2, Item 246)
- Garrison, John. Account book, 1844-1857 (Box 6, Item 615)
  Item returned. No photocopy of the 288 page document seems to have been retained with the collection.
- Phillipstown, Putnam County, NY census (3 volumes; oversize), 1845 (Volume Clark 2, Item 742-744)
- Slauson, Betsey. Summons to appear for probate. Newburgh, Orange County, 1846 October 14 (Box 3, Item 457)
- Barnstable County, MA. Letter to Frederick Scudder, treasurer of Barnstable County, 1847 June 1 (Box 2, Item 298)
  Assessor's notes regarding town of Orleans.
- Cronk, William H. Obligation to John Lee. Fairfax County, 1847 July 1 (Box 3, Item 328)
  States that a slave is used as collateral.
- Shuit, Morgan, Esq. and Mead. Assorted receipts. Highland Mills, Orange County, 1847-1859 (Box 2, Item 230)
  31 receipts.
- Savallette, Capt. E. Letter of certification for Burgess P. Allen, master of arms. US Frigate Congress, Hampton Roads, VA, 1849 January 26 (Box 5, Item 581)
- Van Wyck, William and Augusta. Deed with John Bailey Montross. East Fishkill, Dutchess County, 1851 April 21 (Box 4, Item 564)
- Sist. John (Mr.). Invoice from American Glass Company, 1852 February 2 (Box 1, Item 90)
- Hudson River Railroad. Broadside, 1853 October 3 (Box 2, Item 249)
  Photocopy.
- Collabar Farm. Diary, 1856 (Box 2, Item 182)
- Highland County, NY. Broadside. Proposal for new county, Highland County. Journal Printing Office. Newburgh, NY, 1860 (Box 6, Item 624)
- Cronck, Lorenzo. Letter to his wife. Camp Scott, Alexandria, VA, 1861 August 2 (Box 3, Item 350)
- Clark, Aaron R. Letter to his mother. West Point, 1861 December 11 (Box 5, Item 600)
- Clark, Aaron R. Letter to his mother. West Point, 1861 December 20 (Box 5, Item 599)
  Original returned, photocopy only. States that the army is heading to Washington.
- Clark, Aaron R. Letter to mother. Washington, DC, 1862 February 22 (Box 5, Item 609)
- Clark, Aaron R. Letter to mother. Engineer Quarters, Washington, DC, 1862 March 16 (Box 5, Item 605)
- Clark, Aaron R. Letter to mother. Yorktown Hospital, VA, 1862 May (Box 5, Item 606)
- Village of Newburgh. Notes in .50, .25, .10, .05 denominations. R. Stirling, President. T. King, Treasurer, 1862 October 15 (Box 4, Item 558)
- Fish, Hamilton. Letter to Thomas C. Acton, Esq. In the Highlands, Putnam County, NY, 1863 January 3 (Box 2, Item 201)
  Enclosure of $200 check.
- Clark, Aaron R. Letter to parents. Headquarters, camp near Falmouth, VA, 1863 May 1 (Box 5, Item 603)
- Commissary Department. Assorted papers regarding pay for workers making uniforms. West Point, NY, 1864 July 18 (Box 3, Item 419)
- Eustis, I.B., A.A. General. Notice to Capt. Jno Fletcher of Court Martial to convene on 6/27/1864. Headquarters, Army of Tennessee, in the field near Marietta, GA, 1864 June 23 (Box 5, Item 582)
- Smith, Chas., President of Highland Union Cemetery Association, deed to Oliver Coruk (?), 1864 May 21 (Box 1, Item 120)
- Arthur, Timothy Shay, American author. Letter to William A. Baker. Philadelphia, PA, 1865 March 2 (Box 1, Item 27)
- Hudson River Pottery receipt for Messrs. D.C. Pollard & Co, 1868 (Box 1, Item 118)
- Payroll of persons employed in cadets' laundry. West Point, NY, 1875 December (Box 4, Item 516)
- West Point. Printed form for album, 1877 (Box 2, Item 242)
- Cronk, Oliver H., son of Oliver Cronk, deceased. Letters of administration. Orange County, NY, 1878 January 24 (Box 4, Item 492)
  Regarding powers to disburse father's estate.
- Hudson, D. R. life insurance policy of Global Mutual Life Insurance Company, 1878 March 1 (Box 1, Item 154)
- Wallace, John A. Certification of Oliver H. Cronk as Justice of the Peace. Orange County, 1879 January 2 (Box 3, Item 433)
- Vizay, L.W. Receipt of payment from US Military Academy. West Point, NY, 1880 August 28 (Box 4, Item 496)
  Regarding dancing instruction.
- Vizay, L.W. Receipt of payment from US Military Academy. West Point, NY, 1881 August 25 (Box 4, Item 494)
  Regarding payment for teaching dancing to cadets.
- Vizay, L.W. Receipt of payment from US Military Academy. West Point, NY, 1882 August 25 (Box 4, Item 495)
- Vizay, L.W. Receipt of payment from US Military Academy. West Point, NY, 1883 August 25 (Box 4, Item 501)
- Vizay, L.W. Receipt of payment from US Military Academy. West Point, NY, 1884 August 25 (Box 4, Item 493)
- George, Richard, Sup't of Mines, Chester Iron Company. Letter and statement to Charles Clark, Esq. Dover, NJ, 1886 May 26 (Box 6, Item 627)
- Vizay, L.W. Receipt of payment from US Military Academy. West Point, NY, 1887 August 25 (Box 4, Item 497)
- Vizay, L.W. Receipt of payment from US Military Academy. West Point, NY, 1888 August 25 (Box 4, Item 498)
- Vizay, L.W. Receipt of payment from US Military Academy. West Point, NY, 1890 August 25 (Box 4, Item 499)
- Taft, William Howard, Secretary of War. Quartermaster's Powerhouse and Stable Cover. Headquarters, US Military Academy, West Point, NY, 1906 July 7 (Box 5, Item 578)
  Includes presidential signature.
- Cooper, T.M., Silversmith. Receipt for M.P. Parks (Box 1, Item 158)
  Folder contains part of a prayer and newsclipping regarding portrait of General Scott. Dated June 29, 18?
- Bowks, John. Letter to John Ritter. Engineer Camp, Army Potomac near Richmond (Box 5, Item 604)
  Regarding sickness of son. Dated June 2.
- Meagher, Elizabeth Townsend. Letter to Colonel Francis Rotch. Southfield, Orange County (Box 1, Item 40)
  Original returned, photocopy only. Dated September 15.
- Clinton, Sir Henry. Certificate of Loyalty to the King of William Bayard (Box 1, Item 53)
  Dated February 20.
- Duncan, Peter and John Morison. Discharge note, undated (Box 1, Item 3)
- Redford Glass Co. note. 25 cent denomination. Redford, NY (Box 1, Item 63)
- Redford Glass Co. note. 50 cent denomination. Redford, NY (Box 1, Item 64)
- Redford Glass Co. note. 75 cent denomination. Redford, NY (Box 1, Item 65)
- Vermont Glass Factory note. $1.50. Samuel Swift, President (Box 1, Item 79)
- Vermont Glass Factory note. $1. Samuel Swift, President. Pay to L. Smith (Box 1, Item 83)
- Hudson, William. Partial will (Box 1, Item 150)
- Hudson, William. Partial document (Box 1, Item 151)
  Business property interests.
- Wickham, William. Legal notations regarding controversy on Great Island tract. Deed to Samuel S. Seward and others (Box 2, Item 197)
  Wawayanda patent.
- Knight, R., Aide de Camp. Express order to His Excellency General Howe. Headquarters (Box 2, Item 203)
  Orders that no one harm Stephen Loring (?) in person or property.
- Marquis de Lafayette. Commemorative ribbons for visit in 1820s (Box 2, Item 209)
- Howard, Nathaniel, master of ship James. Report and manifest of cargo on board (Box 2, Item 213)
  Laden at Port of London.
- Roe, John. Letter to Joseph Roe of Warwick (Box 2, Item 220)
- Knox, Henry. Letter to Dr. Thornton (oversize) (Box 2, Item 285)
  Regarding dinner invitation.
- Dayton, Horatio. Letter to Colonel Rochefontaine (Box 2, Item 294)
  Regarding William Gilbert.
- Clinton, George. Autograph (Box 3, Item 323)
- Clinton, George. Autograph (Box 3, Item 324)
- Roesell, Ludwig. Letter to Captain Dederick. West Camp (Box 3, Item 339)
  Letter states that he is too sick to serve.
- Pickering, Timithy. Invoice due from the United States (Box 3, Item 384)
- Skinner, Abraham, Commissioner General of Prisoners. A general return of British Officers taken prisoners at Yorktown (Box 3, Item 389)
- Ecker, Wolvert. Obligation. Ulster County (Box 3, Item 440)
  Fragment; Louis DuBois bond for $500.
- Foord, Lemuell. Tea receipt (Box 3, Item 447)
- Redford Glass Company. Three cents. Redford (Box 3, Item 450)
- Redford Glass Company. Coupons. New York (Box 3, Item 456)
- Recipes for cures for cholera, jaundice and pains (Box 4, Item 537)
- Buell, Aaron. Receipt for 42 heads of cattle to Ebenezer Foote (Box 4, Item 542)
- Forsyth, James. Letter to Ebenezer Foote (Box 4, Item 548)
  Furnish butchers.
- Worthington, Asa. Letter to Ebenezer Foote (Box 4, Item 550)
  Commands for slave query.
- Worthington, Asa. Letter to Brother Fegg (Foote) (Box 4, Item 551)
  Why reclusive.
- Worthington, Asa. Letter to Ebenezer Foote (Box 4, Item 552)
  Lend horse.
- Leary & Getz, publishers. Subscription book: Publications by Leary & Getz. Philadelphia (Box 4, Item 556)
  Contains diary entries, clippings, and poetry.
- Rapelye, Peter and Jacob. Deed with John Schenck. Fishkill, Dutchess County (Box 4, Item 563)
  Incomplete.
- Faurot, Campbell, agent of the Washington Monument Society. Certificate of contribution (Box 4, Item 567)
- Settlers of Jamestown. Signatures (Box 5, Item 613)
  Seven signatures of Jamestown, Virginia settlers.
- Crosby, Enoch. Pension Papers. John Audre. Letter to Washington regarding manner of his execution. The Daily Star. Newspaper clipping Methodist Episcopal Church in New Rochelle. Facsimiles (Box 6, Item 614)
  Facsimiles bound in book.
- Mackinaw Ice Chests. Advertisement. Joseph Van Cleft Hardware, Newburgh, NY (Box 6, Item 626)
- McDonel, Patrick. Deed. Orange County (Box 3, Item 441)
  Fragments.
- Deeds for Kingston, NY (Oversize) (Box OS-Small, Item 616)
- John Jansoon. Americae Pars Meridionalis (Oversize map), circa 1656 (Folder OS-Medium, Item 658)
- Items not listed in finding aid (1 of 3), 1642-1863 (Box 6, Item 634-704)
  Box 6 also holds items numbered 634-704, which are not listed in this finding aid.
- Items not listed in finding aid (2 of 3), 1748-1875 (Box 7, Item 705-735)
- Items not listed in finding aid (3 of 3), 1744-1891 (Box 8, Item 736-795)
  Items 742-744 are the oversize Phillipsburg census of 1845 and are shelved separately from this box. They are listed above in this finding aid.